Realms of Gold: A Catalogue of Maps in the Library of the American Philosophical Society Part I: Manuscript Maps Misc.Maps
American Philosophical Society
Miscellaneous Manuscript Maps
1747-1948
Misc.Maps
American Philosophical Society
100.0 Item(s)
A listing of miscellaneous manuscript maps that are not associated with any particular collections.
Approximately 100 items.
Scope and Contents note
Although most of the Library's manuscript maps are parts of collections, there are almost one hundred individual manuscript maps which were catalogued and filed with the Library's collection of printed maps.
Early American History Note
The APS large map collection contains numerous maps from early America.
Maps; Maps and Surveys; Miscellaneous; Pennsylvania History; Surveying and Maps
- Individually Catalogued Manuscript Maps (Not in Collections)
  - Plot of adjusted survey [of] Moravian road: Authorized: Court of Quarter-Sessions, New Town [Pennsylvania]., 11 June 1747; 649: 1747: P376mor: Small; Photograph, July 1963.; Size: 26 x 34.4 cm.; Craig, Thomas; Gray, George; Greeg, Robert
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Presented by John Robert Connelly, December 1964.
    Scope and Contents note
    Annotated: "From the King's road near Bethlehem to the Mahoning Creek passing near the Healing Waters beyond the Blue Mountain."
    See: John Robert Connelly, "Independent confirmation of the magnetic declination 1737-1738" (typescript, 2 pages, 1963).
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 32 (1).
  - Northampton County [Pennsylvania], 1752; 649.757: 1752: N816efd: Large; Scale: 1 inch = 5 mi.; Size: 66 x 68 cm.
    Note: This map is an 1854 copy of a 1752 map. Includes also the following counties: Lehigh, Schuylkill, Columbia, Carbon, Monroe, Pike, Luzerne, Wyoming, Bradford, Susquehanna, and Wayne. See: A. D. Chidsey, Jr., The Penn patents in the forks of the Delaware. Easton, Pa.: John S. Correll: 1937 (929.4: H39).
    Realms of Gold, 32 (2).
  - [Middle Atlantic states, showing rivers and mountains and location of sea shells on the tops of the mountains], [1750s]; 650: [ca.1750s]: At61mvc: Small; Size: 31 x 38 cm.; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Presented by Benjamin Franklin.
    As early as 1741, John Bartram sent some fossil sea shells to Sir Hans Sloan; other shells were sent to his London friend Peter Collinson in 1742. He wrote to Collinson in 1743 or 1744 that he had observed such fossils everywhere, "even on the top of the mountain that separates the waters of Susquehanna and St. Lawrence." (William Darlington, Memorials of John Bartram and Humphry Marshall [Philadelphia: 1849], p. 169.) Bartram was used to making rough maps of his travels and he made no pretense of being a competent surveyor. He apologized to Collinson for a map which he said was "Clumsily done, —having neither proper instruments nor convenient time," since he was drawing by the early light of dawn or by candlelight.
    Franklin wrote his friend Jared Eliot on 16 July 1747 of Bartram's discoveries:
    The great Apalachian Mountains, which run from York [Hudson] River back of these Colonies to the Bay of Mexico, show in many Places near the highest Parts of them, Strata Sea Shells, in some Places the marks of them are in the solid Rocks. 'Tis certainly the Wreck of a World we live on! We have Specimens of those Sea shell Rocks broken off near the Tops of those Mountains, brought and deposited in our Library [the Library Company of Philadelphia] as Curiosities. If you have not seen the like, I'll send you a Piece. ( The Papers of Benjamin Franklin [New Haven: Yale University Press: 1961], vol. 3, p. 169.)
    The endorsement on the back reads, in Franklin's hand: "Mr. Bartram's Map very curious."
    Realms of Gold, 32 (3).
  - Pennsylvania, [ca. 1765]; 649: [ca.1765]: P376pmj: Small; Photostat in 4 pieces.; Size: 86.1 x 102.4 cm.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (4).
  - West Florida, part of E. Florida, Georgia, part of So. Carolina including... Chactaw, Chickasaw and Creek nations with [ ] Pensacola through ye Creek nation 16 August and Charles Stuart... superintendent of Indian affairs., [ca. 1772]; 636.5: [ca. 1772]: St97fLa: Book map; 30 sectional photostats.; Size: 120 x 90 cm.; Romans, Bernard; Taitt, David
    From original in William L. Clements Library, 1940.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (5).
  - Sketch of the action on the heights of Charles Town 17 June 1775, between his magestys troops under the command of M. General Howe and a large body of American rebel's, 644: 1775: D325 chm: Small; Size: 34.7 x 51.2 cm.; Colored.; De Berniere, Henry; Dearborn, Henry, 1751-1829
    Annotated: "The parts in red are corrections of the original by Maj. Gen. Dearborn."
    The signature of J. V. N. Throop is on the map. Printed version is in the same folder.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (6).
  - [Maps of Lake Superior and the Canadian Lakes], [ca. 1775-1777]; 626.2: 1777: Su77mcp: Small; Four maps on one folio sheet.; Size: 37 x 22.8 cm.
    The sheet contains the following maps (No. 1 is not present):
    "No. 2. From map of North America by Eman Brown, geog. to his majesty, 1775; in Jefferey's atlas of 1776."
    "No. 3. Map of North America from d'Anville published by Sayer and others. London 1775; in Jefferey's atlas of 1776."
    "No. 4. Map of the British empire by Samuel Dunn; published by Robert Sayer, 1774, London in Jefferey's atlas."
    "No. 5. From a map of the British colonies in North America; engraved by William Faden, 1777."
    Realms of Gold, 32 (7).
  - A collection of plans...in the province of New Jersey, 1777-1782; 648: 1777-1782: H55c: Small; 15 maps. Reproductions.; Sizes: Various.; Hills, John, surveyor
    Reprinted from the originals in the Library of Congress for the Portolan Press by the Meriden Gravure Company, 1976.
    In addition to Hills, the maps were created by cartographers: Grant, A. Sutherland, B. Morgan, A. Dennis, Rue, A. B. Dunhan, Taylor, Skinner, I. Williams, T. Milliadge and J. Fisher.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (8).
  - [Plan of Yorktown, Virginia, depicting the armies when Cornwallis surrendered], 22 October 1781 - 28 October 1781; 654: 1781: B321ytv: Small; 3 pieces (preliminary drafts).; Sizes of paper: 44.3 x 56.8 cm; 31.7 x 43.5 cm; 30.5 x 43.7 cm.; Colored.; Bauman, Sebastian
    Presented by Richard Randolph, 7 October 1831.
    The disposition of the troops and fleets are carefully delineated. This map was published in Philadelphia in 1782.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (9).
  - Les deux parties française et espagnol de St. Domingue réduites en triangles, lieues marines carrées et carraux de cent pas sur cent d'après la carte gravée sur une plus grande échelle... Madrid, 1784; 724: 1784: L885fed: Small; Scale: 50 Lieues marines de 2851½ toises chacune ou 4888 2/7 Pas.; Size: 32.6 x 37.9 cm.; Colored.; López, Juan, 1765-1825
    Annotated: "Explication des base, perpendiculaire et surface de chaque triangle: Calcul des deux parties de St. Domingue et islots adjacents: Résultat en lieues marines carrées et en carrouse de cent pas carrés."
    Realms of Gold, 32 (10).
  - Mapa de las cerc de Mexico que comprehende todos sus lugares y rios, las lagunos de Tescuco, Chalco, Xochimiles, Ste. Christobal Zumpago, 1785; 707: 1785: L885mmr: Small; Scale: Leguas de une hora de camino a de 20 al grada.; Size: 37.2 x 40 cm.; López, Juan, 1765-1825
    This map contains the names of the lagoons, rivers, mountains, towns, etc.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (11).
  - [Parts of Glynn and McIntosh counties, Georgia, showing the Alatamaha and Mud Rivers, Buttermilk Sound and Hampton Creek], [1786?]; 658.751: 1786?: G293arg: Small; Size of paper: 38 x 48.1 cm.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (12).
  - Maryland. Taken principally from Fry and Jefferson, 1793; 652: 1793: M365mfj: Small; Scale: 69½ miles to a degree.; Size: 32.6 x 41.9 cm.; Fry, Joshua, 1700 (ca.)-1754; Jefferson, Peter, 1708-1757
    This map contains far more settlements and better definition of streams than the 1751 map by Joshua Fry and Peter Jefferson. The inset shows Alleganey ridge.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (13).
  - The [state of] New Jersey according to the best authorities, 1793; 648: 1793: N466suj: Large; Scale: 1 degree = 69½ British miles.; Size: 59 x 21.5 cm.
    A note in the folder reads: "Nota Bene. This map should be used with discretion for the following reasons... ." See also information furnished by Lewis M. Haupt, 16 March 1917 (typescript with the maps).
    Realms of Gold, 32 (14).
  - Carta esférica de las costas de la Nueva Galicia, reconocida desde el surgidero de Mazatlan asta el Cava Corrientes, 1795; 706.2: 1795: N176ngm: Small; Size: 50.8 x 35.5 cm.; Narváez, José, b. 1768?
    Narváez was "Primer Pilato de la Marina Nacional."
    Realms of Gold, 32 (15).
  - [Map showing parts of the intendencias of Vera Cruz, Yucatan, Chiapas, Oaxaca, etc., reaching from the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of Tehuantepec], [ca. 1795]; 707: ca.1795: M575tco: Small; Scale: 2 cm. = 5 leagues.; Size: 38.3 x 43.4 cm.
    Annotated: "Los grados de Longitud y Latitud se han Pueste seguin el calculo de Baron de Homboldt."
    Realms of Gold, 32 (16).
  - [Map showing the area between Guadalaxxara and Salamanca, Mexico], [ca. 1795]; 706: [ca.1795]: M575gsm: Small; Size: 40 x 43.5 cm.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (17).
  - [Mexico: showing parts of the states from Vera Cruz to Toluca, with the bishoprics of Oaxaca to the south and the archbishopric of Mexico and the bishopric of Puebla to the west: also, "Partidos" of Antiqua, Zalape, Mizantla, Cordova, Cosamaluapan, Tehuacan, Haujapa, Tepixi de la Seda, Tepeaca, Orizava, Los Llanos, Tezuitlan, Telela y Xonotla and Zacatlan], [ca. 1795]; 708: [ca.1795]: M575vms: Large; Scale: Escala de [docc?] leguas.; Size: 44.6 x 63.5 cm.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (18).
  - State of Massachusetts. Compiled from the best authorities, [1795]; 644: [1795]: L585smc: Large; Scale: 1 degree = 69½ miles.; Size: 37 x 49.4 cm.; Lewis, Samuel, 1753 or 4-1822
    Provenance: Presented by Mathew Carey, 18 October 1805.
    The American Philosophical Society Transactions (vol. 6) state that Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography were compiled." This is one of those maps. See: William Guthrie, The general atlas for Carey's edition of his geography improved. (Philadelphia: Carey: 1795).
    Wheat: 213.
    See: M. Carey, Carey's American atlas. Philadelphia: Carey, 1796, no. 5.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (18a).
  - The state of Virginia from the best authorities. Engraved for Carey's edition of Guthrie's geography, improved, [1795]; 654: [1795]: L585vcg: Large; Scale: 1 degree = 69½ American miles.; Size: 34.4 x 53.1 cm.; Lewis, Samuel, 1753 or 4-1822
    Adapted from the map of Virginia in the general atlas for Carey's edition of Guthrie's geography improved (Philadelphia: Carey, 1795). See also: Notes on the state of Virginia, by Thomas Jefferson. 3rd American edition. (New York: M.L. and W.A. Davis, for Furman and Loudon: 1801).
    The American Philosophical Society Transactions (vol. 6) state that Mathew Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography was compiled," on 18 October 1805. This is part of that gift.
    Wheat: 568.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (19).
  - The Waldo patent, [ca. 1795]; 641: [ca. 1795]: W149wpm: Large; Scale: 1 inch = 3 miles.; Size: 105.7 x 73.1 cm.; Colored.; Carleton, Osgood, 1742-1816
    Realms of Gold, 32 (20).
  - Map of the Tennassee government, formerly part of North Carolina. Taken chiefly from surveys by Gen. D. Smith and others, [1795]; 662: [1795]: Sm5.3: Small; 2 pieces.; Scale: 1 inch = 14 miles.; Size: 33.7 x 83.7 cm.; Smith, David
    Knoxville and Nashville are shown, as well as public roads, Indian boundaries, Indian towns, etc. The width of the river is in yards.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (21).
  - A map of the Tennasee government, formerly part of North Carolina, taken chiefly from surveys by Gen[era]l D. Smith and others, [1795]; 662: [1795]: Sm5.1: Large; Scale: 1 inch = 22 miles.; Size: 24.4 x 53.5 cm.; Colored.; Smith, David
    See also an engraving of the above by "J.T. Scott, Sculp" that was "engraved for Carey's American edition of Guthrie's geography improved." There are numerous manuscript notations on this printed map.
    The American Philosophical Society Transactions (vol. 6) state that Mathew Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography was compiled," on 18 October 1805. This is part of that gift. See: William Guthrie, The general atlas for Carey's edition of his geography improved. (Philadelphia: Carey, 1795).
    Wheat: 650
    Realms of Gold, 32 (21a).
  - [Map of western Pennsylvania and eastern Ohio showing the locations of early Indian paths and towns of the Christian Indian missions...between 1772 and 1787], 1796; 649: 1796: H365paoh: Large; Size: 33.4 x 59.7 cm.; Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823
    Facsimile of an original manuscript.
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Reproduced and copyrighted by the Western Reserve Historical Society, Cleveland, Ohio: 1968.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (22).
  - The state of Pennsylvania. Reduced (with permission) from Reading Howell's large map, [ca. 1796]; 649: [ca.1796]: L585rhm: Large; Scale: 1 degree = 69½ American miles.; Size: 29.6 x 47.1 cm.; Howell, Reading, 1743-1827; Lewis, Samuel, 1753 or 4-1822
    Presented by Mathew Carey, 18 October 1805.
    Wheat: 448
    Realms of Gold, 32 (23).
  - The state of Rhode Island; compiled from the surveys and observations of Caleb Harris, [1796]; 645: [1796]: H243ri: Small; Scale: 1 inch = 4½ miles.; Size: 35.4 x 24.3 cm.; Harris, Caleb; Harris, Harding
    Wheat: 250.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (24).
  - Carte de la partie Française de l'isle de St. Domingue, [1800]; 725: [1800]: Sa27fsd: Small; Scale: 5 cm. = 10 toises.; Size: 44 x 55.2 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    This map was acquired with the purchase of a large collection of maps about St. Domingue and other Gulf of Mexico areas from Henry Schenk Tanner on 14 December 1835.
    Information about George de Bois St. Lys and the significance of these maps may be found in James E. McClellan, Colonialism and science in the old regime: the case of Saint Domingue (forthcoming).
    Realms of Gold, 32 (25).
  - Carte de l'isle de Cuba, comprenant les jurisdictions de Philippine, de la Havane, des quatre Bourgs, de la ville de St. Marie du Port au Prince, de Bayamo et de St. Yago do Cuba, 1800; 723: 1800: S27phs: Large; Scale: 20 lieues marines au dégré.; Size: 49.2 x 89.6 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de; López, Juan, 1765-1825
    Realms of Gold, 32 (26).
  - Carte de l'isle de la Gonave et de la côte depuis la baye de l'Artibonite jusqu'à celle des Baradaires dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa27arf: Large; Size: 57.7 x 88.9 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (27).
  - Carte de l'isle de Puerto Rico, 1800; 728: 1800: Sa27cd: Large; Scale: Echelle de dix lieues Marines, de vingt au dégré.; Size of paper: 54.3 x 100 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de; López de Vargas Machuca, Tomás, 1731-1802
    Realms of Gold, 32 (28).
  - Carte de l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 724: 1800: S27std: Large; Scale: Lieues marines de vingt au dégré.; Size: 49.6 x 90.3 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (29).
  - [Chart of the coast of southern Florida, the Bahamas and Cuba], [ca. 1800]; 659: [ca. 1800]: F373cfc: Large; Size: 44.2 x 66.3 cm.; Colored.; Ferrer, Jose Joaquin de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (29a).
  - A map of part of Onondaga Lake, and its vicinity, in the state of New York. From actual survey, [ca. 1800]; 647: [ca. 1800]: On66ol: Small; Scale: 1 inch = 765⅙ yards.; Size: 27.5 x 40.5 cm.; Colored.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (30).
  - [Pennsylvania], [ca. 1800]; 649: [ca. 1800]: P376pen: Large; Scale: 1 inch = 15 miles.; Size: 30.6 x 51.8 cm.
    Annotated: "Explanation: County towns, villages, forges and mills, houses, roads and portages, roads to be opened and improved on the straightest line practicable."
    Northumberland and Allegany Counties occupy a disproportionately large area of the state.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (31).
  - Plan de la baye de Dame Marie dans l'isle de St. Domingue...pour M. E. Stevens, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa27dmd: Large; Scale: 2.9 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 53.3 x 64.7 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (32).
  - Plan de la baye de l'Acul dans la partie du nord de l'isle de Saint Domingue...pour Mr E. Stevens, Consul G[ener]al, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa27acu: Large; Scale: 2.4 cm. = 300 toises.; Size: 53.3 x 63.9 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (33).
  - Plan de la baye de Samana dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Ad11brd: Large; Scale: Cinq lieues de trois milles chacune.; Size: 55.3 x 99 cm.; Colored.; Advenier de Breuilly, A. P.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (34).
  - Plan de la baye des Irois dans l'isle de St. Domingue...pour M. E. Stevens, Consul G[ener]al, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa27iro: Large; Scale: 2 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 53.5 x 64.5 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (35).
  - Plan de la baye d'Ocoa dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Ad11sdo: Large; Scale: 1.9 cm. = 400 toises.; Size: 59.4 x 95.3 cm.; Colored.; Advenier de Breuilly, A. P.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (36).
  - Plan de la baye et du bourg de Tiburon dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: [ca.1800]: Sa27bbt: Small; Scale: 7 cm. = 500 toises.; Size: 39.7 x 56.5 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (37).
  - Plan de la baye, ville et forts de St. Yago dans l'isle de Cuba, 1800; 723: 1800: S27dsy: Large; Scale: 2.2 cm. = 200 toises.; Size: 48.1 x 63.4 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (38).
  - Plan de la ville des Cayes dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: [1800]: Sa27pvc: Large; Scale: 1.3 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 41.7 x 50.1 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (39).
  - Plan de la ville de Jeremie et de ses environs, [1800]; 725: [1800]: Sa27pvj: Large; Scale: 2.8 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 46 x 47.3 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (40).
  - Plan de la ville de St. Marc dans l'isle de St. Domingue, [ca. 1800]; 725: [ca.1800]: Sa27pvm: Small; Scale: 2.6 cm. = 560 toises.; Size: 43.7 x 60.1 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (41).
  - Plan de la ville de Santo Domingo, 1800; 726.971: 1800: Sa27pvs: Large; Scale: 1.8 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 55.5 x 71.6 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de; López, Juan, 1765-1825
    Realms of Gold, 32 (42).
  - Plan de la ville, des rades et des environs du Port au Prince dans l'isle de St. Domingue, [ca. 1800]; 725: [ca.1800]: Sa27ppd: Small; Scale: 5.5 cm. = 200 toises.; Size: 44.4 x 61.5 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (43).
  - Plan de la ville du Cap Français dans l'isle de St. Domingue, [1800]; 725: [1800]: Sa27cfid: Large; Scale: 1.8 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 48.8 x 62 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (44).
  - Plan de la ville et de la baye du Fort Dauphin dans l'isle St. Domingue, [1800]; 725: [1800]: Sa27fds: Large; Scale: 1 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 41.5 x 60.3 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (45).
  - Plan de la ville et de la rade du Petit Goave dans l'isle de St. Domingue, [1800]; 725: [1800]:S27rpg: Large; Scale: 2.1 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 39.5 x 59 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (46).
  - Plan de la ville et des environs de Jacmel, dans l'isle de Saint Domingue assiégée par le Général en chef Toussaint l'Overture et defendue par le G[énér]al André Rigaud revolté en 1800. Avec la position des troupes qui la bloquent et des batteries qui ont été dressées contre elle, 725: 1800: Sa27jdt: Large; Scale: 1.9 cm. = 200 toises.; Size: 55 x 79.5 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (47).
  - Plan de la ville et de port de Samana dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Ad11psd: Large; Scale: 1.7 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 41.1 x 60.6 cm.; Colored.; Advenier de Breuilly, A. P.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (48).
  - Plan de l'entrée de la baye de St. Yago dans l'isle de Cuba, 1800; 723: 1800: S27bsy: Large; Scale: 2.3 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 49.8 x 63 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (49).
  - Plan du bourg de La Croix des Bouquets dans l'isle de St. Domingue, [1800]; 725: [1800]: Sa27cdb: Large; Scale: 1.8 cm. = 200 toises.; Size: 41 x 87 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Detail: Le Fort la Constitution servant de citadelle à la Croix de Bouquets.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (50).
  - Plan du Port Français dans la partie du nord de Saint Domingue...pour Mr. E. Stevens, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa25fra: Large; Scale: 3.4 cm. = 50 toises.; Size of paper: 53.3 x 64.9 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (51).
  - Plan d'une partie de la Plaine du Cap Français et de la côte, depuis la baye de l'Acul, jusques et après le bourg de la Petite Anse, dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Sa27cf: Large; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 400 toises.; Size of paper: 57.3 x 87 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (52).
  - Plan d'une partie de la plaine du fond de l'isle à Vache et de la côte, depuis de Grande Baye du Mesle, jusqu'à la pointe de l'Abacou, dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1800; 725: 1800: Ad11pLv: Large; Scale: Une lieue marine de 2833 toises.; Size: 53.4 x 87.9 cm.; Colored.; Advenier de Breuilly, A. P.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (53).
  - Survey of the lands adjoining Monticello in Albemarle county, belonging to Nicholas Meriwether and Abraham Lewis, and later to Meriwether Lewis, [ca. 1800]; 654: [ca. 1800]: J354acv: Small; Photograph.; Size: 39.1 x 29 cm.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    From original manuscript in the Library of Congress.
    Realms of Gold, 32 (54).
  - Carte réduite des débouquemens de St. Domingue desinée d'après celle levée en 1785, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27cpb: Large; Size of paper: 58 x 97.7 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de; Puységur, A.-H.-A. de Chastenet, comte de, (Antoine-Hyacinthe-Anne), 1752-1807
    Realms of Gold, 32 (55).
  - Plan de la baye des Gonaives dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27bg: Large; Scale: 1.8 cm. = 30 toises.; Size: 56.3 x 69.8 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (56).
  - Plan de la baye du Fond la Grange dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27fLg: Large; Scale: 3.6 cm. = 100 toises.; Size: 46.1 x 62.4 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (57).
  - Plan de la baye du Moustique dans la partie nord de l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27mou: Large; Scale: 1.9 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 43.7 x 62.5 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (58).
  - Plan de la baye du Port à l'Ecu dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27pbe: Large; Scale: 2.6 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 50.9 x 61.8 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (59).
  - Plan de la ville de Jacmel dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27uj: Large; Scale: 2.8 cm. = 50 toises.; Size: 49.8 x 64.9 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (60).
  - Plan de la ville et de la baye de St. Marc dans l'isle de St. Domingue, 1801; 725: 1801: Sa27vsm: Large; Scale: 3.2 cm. = 300 toises.; Size: 49.5 x 70.7 cm.; Colored.; Bois St. Lys, Georges Joseph de
    Realms of Gold, 32 (61).